# Edoardo Ghini Robotics Engineer

#### **BRIEF DESCRIPTION**

Curious and self-confident person, level-headed and quite an experimenter. Passionate about programming and believing it to be a form of art. Fascinated by mysteries of science and firm believer in technological progress. Enthusiastic about the latest academic discoveries in my field of expertise. Looking forward to learning more about Neuroscience and Human Consciousness and combine them together with Robotics and Artificial Intelligence.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

CURRENT, FROM OCT 2020 (FT)

INRIA, French national research institute Robotics Engineer

Developed a system from the ground up to teleoperate an industrial robot in hazardous environments. Each module of the pipeline is written in C++ and it is containerized with **Docker** and communicate through **ROS** middleware. Dynamics of the system is simulated in a **digital** twin using dart and gazebo. Joint-space and Cartesian control of the robot through pinocchio and tsid libraries. Designed a GUI for teleoperation with C++ library *ImGui* that introduces interactive **automation** of the task. Experience in URDF creation, modern C++ frameworks and libraries interfacing and acquaintance with robots of the lab: franka manipulator & talos humanoid robot.

FEB 2019 - OCT 2019 (FT)

# La Sapienza, University of Rome Master's Thesis

Implemented a robotic system to achieve autonomous navigation (SLAM) in an urban environment of a mobile robot equipped with a **3D-LIDAR** laser sensor. The whole project has been implemented in C++ adopting the ROS build system. High-level features are extracted from the 3Dpoint cloud and categorized in geometric primitives. The sensor data is processed using the primitives in order to compute the trajectory of the robot. Usesd a probabilistic approach that involves using the Gaussian assumption and a Least Square formulation. The work has been developed in collaboration with the Robotics Laboratory of La Sapienza University.

Master thesis link

MAR 2016 - JUL 2016 (FT)

Translated

## Back-end developer

During this internship, I was responsible for the codebase of a web application: Matecat, written in PHP. I developed unit-tests to certify the correctness of the core of the application. Brought code coverage percentage from 0% to 25%. Worked with databases and client-server communications: MySQL and Apache. Learned how to work in agile teams, following scrum principles. Acquired deep knowledge of advanced testing techniques: **mock objects**, **reflection**, and **TDD**.

Bachelor thesis link

Nancy, France

+33 6 73 03 31 71 (FR)

ghiniedoardo@gmail.com ()

github.com/dinies linkedin.com/in/dinies

#### **EDUCATION**

2016 - 2019 **MScEng** 

FINAL GRADE 103 /110

Master in Artificial Intelligence and Robotics

La Sapienza, University of Rome

2013 - 2016

FINAL GRADE 95 /IIO Computer Engineering Roma Tre University

# PROGRAMMING SKILLS

C++, python, LATEX, Javascript LANGUAGES

Java, bash, MATLAB, PHP

variadic templates, move semantic C++20

smartpointers, concepts, lambdas

DESIGN OOP, polymorphism, functional programming

TDD, reflection, mock objects, googletest TESTING

OpenCV, tensoflow, OpenGL, dart, ImGui LIBRARIES

cmake, Docker, git, vim, gdb, valgrind DEVOPS

#### THEORETICAL SKILLS

dynamic systems evolution, quaternions ROBOTICS CONTROL

inverse dynamics, robust control

SLAM, trajectory planning ROBOTIC NAVIGATION obstacle avoidance, filtering

bioinspired networks, CNN MACHINE

spiking neurons, LSTM **LEAR NING** 

multiagent systems, reinforcement learning ARTIFICIAL INTELLIGENCE first order logic, planning and reasoning

operative systems, network protocols COMPUTER

algorithms design, databases SCIENCE

# REFERENCES

Dr. Serena Ivaldi

POSITION Research scientist

**INRIA** EMPLOYER

> serena.ivaldi@inria.fr EMAIL

> > Dr. Giorgio Grisetti

Professor POSITION

EMPLOYER La Sapienza, University of Rome

EMAIL grisetti@diag.uniroma1.it

Italian: native English: IELTS academic cert. Overall band score 7.0 CEFR level C1 French: level A2 Languages:

Privacy: "In compliance with the GDPR and Italian Legislative Decree no. 196 dated 30/06/2003, I hereby authorize the recipient of this document to use and process my personal details for the purpose of recruiting and selecting staff and I confirm to be informed of my rights in accordance to art. 7 of the above mentioned Decree".